Kévin dos Santos Mateus

Póvoa de Varzim, Portugal

918614124

kevinsmateus@outlook.com

Kévin Mateus | LinkedIn in

Kévin Mateus | GitHub

Date of Birth: 14 Febuary 1990

After 7 years as an officer of the Portuguese Air Force working in military aircraft maintenance management, I decided to embrace a new adventure as a Full Stack Developer. With a background in Aeronautical Engineering, I like to welcome new challenges, solve problems and acquire new skills. Available and enthusiastic to work in this new area of programming, based on team/organizational spirit, experience and discipline learned.

Education

MARCH 2023 - SEPTEMBER 2023

<Academia de Código_> A 25-week asynchronous peer-to-peer full-stack online study program. Details on my linkedIn profile

SETEMBER 2020 - OCOTBER 2020

Flight Safety Course/Portuguese <u>Air</u> Force, Alfragide, Lisboa, Portugal Final Score: 18,5/20

SEPTEMBER 2008 - OCTOBER 2014

Master's Degree in Aeronautical Engineering/University of Beira Interior, Covilhã, Portugal

Master's Thesis- "Improvement of mechanical properties of sandwich structures made of composite material" (Final Score: 16/20); Final Degree Average score: 14/20

Skills

Java, Spring MVC, Spring Framework, Programming, Object-Oriented Programming, Web Development, Web Applications, SOA, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, Git, SQL, jUnit, Testing, Agile Methodologies, SCRUM, Maven, Tomcat, ES6, REST API, Java Database Connectivity, Model View-Controller (MVC), React, Outsystems, Service Studio, Low Code.

Projects

MAY 2023 – SEPTEMBER 2023

JavaBank

JavaBank Web App is an ongoing project started at week 13 of The StudIO bootcamp – a full-fledged application reflecting a Bank management system that was built using industry best practices and most useful components of the java ecosystem.

Languages

- Portuguese (Native)
- English (Fluent)

Hobbies

- Sport
- Travel

Professional Experience

NOVEMBER 2014- JANUARY 2022

Equipment Engineer Amkor

JULY 2022 - SEPTEMBER 2023

Equipment Engineer/Amkor Technology, Mindelo

Part of the MEMS project production line from Amkor Technology as an Equipment Engineer, where I was responsible for the management of a technical team that performed maintenance in equipments used for semiconductors encapsulation.

Portuguese Air Force Officer

AUGUST 2019 - JANUARY 2022

Deputy Maintenance Officer/Squadron 504 Falcon 50, Lisbon

Part of the main board on the maintenance department of squadron 504 (Falcon50 Aircraft) from the Portuguese Air Force as Chief of the APC (Planning and Control Area) and Deputy Maintenance Officer, where I was in charge of planning the promptitude of the flight resources necessary to accomplish the squadron's missions, such as VIP Transport, Organ Transplant Transportation and Medical Evacuations (MEDEVAC);

JANUARY 2018 - JULY 2019

Maintenance Officer/Squadron 552 Alouette III e AW119 Koala, Beja

Part of the main board on the maintenance department of squadron 552 from the Portuguese Air Force (Helicopters Alouette III and AW119 Koala) as Chief of the Flight Line Area with the responsibility of ensuring the promptitude of aircraft and their configuration for the different types of squadron missions;

NOVEMBER 2014 - DECEMBER 2017

Chief of the Support Squadron/Material Squadron, Beja

Part of the main board of the Material Squadron as Head of the Aircraft Ground Support and Flight Equipment where all flight equipment maintenance management was of my responsibility.